Sewall Wright Papers 1895-1988 Mss.Ms.Coll.60
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1895-1988; 13.5 Linear feet
  - United States Lines, 1949 (Box Series I-25)
  - University of California (Box Series I-25)
    - University of California, 1942-57 (Box Series I-25)
      Jahn, Theodore L.; Sproul, Robert C.; Hitchock Professor Lectures; Lipman, Charles B.
    - College of Agriculture, 1946-53 (Box Series I-25)
      Briggs, Fred N.; Clausen, Roy E.; Division of Agronomy; Division of Genetics
    - Department of Zoology, 1946-57 (Box Series I-25)
      Ball, Gordon; Moore, Carl B.; Jahn, Theodore L.
  - University of California-Riverside, 1973 (Box Series I-25)
    Vasek, Frank C.; Department of Biology
  - University of Chicago, 1927-1947; 28 folders (Box Series I-25)
    Committee activities; Conferences and symposia -- Darwin Centennial; Educational matters; Fellowships, assistantships; Paleontology; Political issues -- Hitler manifesto; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Teaching; University of Chicago; Zoology
    - Adamstone, F. B., 1947 (Box Series I-25)
      Department of Zoology
    - Allee, Warder Clyde, 1927-35 (Box Series I-25)
    - The Art Committee, 1945 (Box Series I-25)
    - Baluch, Habiballah G., 1936 (Box Series I-25)
    - [Bantilmiz], George W., 1935 (Box Series I-25)
    - Beal, John M, 1935 (Box Series I-25)
    - Bensley, R.R., 1935 (Box Series I-25)
    - Bixler, R.W., 1936 (Box Series I-25)
    - Burton, Ernest D., 1948 (Box Series I-25)
      Distinguished Service Professor; Daines, H. C.
    - Carlson, A. J., 1935 (Box Series I-25)
    - Ferry, Margaret E., 1952 (Box Series I-25)
    - Office of the Registrar, 1949 (Box Series I-25)
    - Reuther, Ann, 1948 (Box Series I-25)
    - Mrs. Scudder, 1951 (Box Series I-25)
    - Shull, C. A., 1935 (Box Series I-25)
    - Simons, Henry C., [1944] (Box Series I-25)
    - Steinbach, H. Burr, 1968 (Box Series I-25)
    - Strozier, Robert M., 1951 (Box Series I-25)
    - Sturtevant, Mary E., 1944 (Box Series I-25)
    - Swift, Harold H., 1944 (Box Series I-25)
    - Tom, 1977 (Box Series I-25)
    - Taliaferro, William H., 1931-1947 (Box Series I-25)
    - University Senate, 1944-51 (Box Series I-25)
    - Wagner, J. H., 1936 (Box Series I-25)
    - Woellner, Robert C., 1951 (Box Series I-25)
    - Woodward, Frederic, 1935 (Box Series I-25)
    - Zeuch, Clara, 1948 (Box Series I-25)
    - Zoology, Department of, 1944 (Box Series I-26)
  - University of Chicago Press (Box Series I-26)
    - Alexander, Mary D., 1956 (Box Series I-26)
    - Bowen, Carroll G., 1960 (Box Series I-26)
    - Hemens, Rollin D., 1945-59 (Box Series I-26)
    - Jordan, W. K., 1941-43 (Box Series I-26)
    - McNeill, John T., 1943-44 (Box Series I-26)
    - Richter, Anders, 1962-65 (Box Series I-26)
    - Veith, Ilza, 1953 (Box Series I-26)
  - University College London, 1950 (Box Series I-26)
    The Galton Lecture
  - University of Illinois, 1961-77 (Box Series I-26)
    Honorary Doctor of Science Degree; Henry, David D.; Janata, A.J,; Mertz, David B.; Tyler Award
  - University of Miami, 1957 (Box Series I-26)
    Miller, E. Morton
  - University of Michigan, 1931-50 (Box Series I-26)
    Laboratory of Vertebrate Biology
  - University of Pennsylvania School of Medicine, 1966-77 (Box Series I-26)
    Forster, Robert E.; Silvers, Willys K.
  - University of Rochester, 1942 (Box Series I-26)
    Honorary Degree; Valentine, Alan
  - University of Texas, 1941 (Box Series I-26)
    Brogan, A. P.
  - University of Virginia, 1955 (Box Series I-26)
    Parson, William
  - University of Wisconsin, 1953-65 (Box Series I-26)
    Scotton, James F.; Honorary Degree; Irwin, M. Robert; Simon, Clarke; Fred, E.B.; Harrington, Frederick Harvey
  - Unknown, 4 folders (Box Series I-26)
    - Folder 1, 1943-46 (Box Series I-26)
    - Folder 2, 1947 (Box Series I-26)
    - Folder 3, 1948 (Box Series I-26)
    - Folder 4, 1949 (Box Series I-26)
  - Van Cleave, H. J., 1931 (Box Series I-26)
  - Vander Meer, Jacques, 1924 (Box Series I-26)
  - Van Ness, Helen J., 1936 (Box Series I-26)
  - Van Nostrand, D, Co., Inc., 1962 (Box Series I-26)
  - Van Valen, Leigh, n. d. (Box Series I-26)
  - Vavi1ov, 1926 (Box Series I-26)
  - Veith, Ilza, 1953 (Box Series I-26)
  - Veldee, M. V., 1947 (Box Series I-26)
  - Vetta, Atam, 1976 (Box Series I-26)
  - Vial, E. E., 1924-26 (Box Series I-26)
  - Villee, Claude A., 1948 (Box Series I-26)
  - Vincent, John H., 1954 (Box Series I-26)
  - Vogel, Harold M., 1946 (Box Series I-26)
  - Vogel, Howard H., Jr., 1951 (Box Series I-26)
  - Von Bonin, Gerhardt, 1931-1932 (Box Series I-26)
  - Von Hofstn, Nilse, 1955 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wachtel, Irwin J., 1939 (Box Series I-26)
  - Waddington, C. H., 1946-1963 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wade, Michael J., 1980 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wagner, F. A., 1949 (Box Series I-26)
    U.S. Lines Co.
  - Wagner, Konrad, 1933-1934 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wahmann, George H. Manufacturing Co., 1946 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wait Richard, 1956 (Box Series I-26)
  - Walker, Norma Ford, 1949 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wallace, 1923 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wallace, Bruce, 1950-1968; 11.0 Item(s) (Box Series I-26)
    Drosophila genetics; Population genetics; Publication -- American Naturalist; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Wallace, Henry A., 1923-1935 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wallbrunn, Henry M., 1953-1963 (Box Series I-26)
  - Walton, H. B., 1920 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wang, Chien-Ming, 1948 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wang, His, 1946-1956 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wantrup, S. V., 1944 (Box Series I-26)
  - Ward, Henry Baldwin, 1916 (Box Series I-26)
  - Warkany, Josef, 1954 (Box Series I-26)
    Wilson, James G.
  - Warren, Katherine Brehme, 1961 (Box Series I-26)
  - Warren, Shields, 1957 (Box Series I-26)
    Muller, Herman J.
  - Washbourne, Carleton, 1963-64 (Box Series I-26)
  - Washburn, S. L., 1952-54 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wassenberg, Harry, 1970 (Box Series I-26)
  - Watanabe, Yisamu, 1951 (Box Series I-26)
  - Waterman, Harriet, 1943 (Box Series I-26)
  - Waterman, Talbot H., 1961 (Box Series I-26)
  - Waters, H. J., 1924 (Box Series I-26)
  - Watson, James D., 1965 (Box Series I-26)
  - Waugh, Dan F., 1943 (Box Series I-26)
  - Waugh, David F., 1951 (Box Series I-26)
  - Weaver, Warren, 1936 (Box Series I-26)
  - Weigel, John C., 1956 (Box Series I-26)
  - Weinstein, Alexander, 1931-47 (Box Series I-26)
  - Weir, Jack A., 1954-74 (Box Series I-26)
  - Weiss, Francis Joseph, 1949 (Box Series I-26)
  - Weiss, Kenneth M., 1974 (Box Series I-26)
  - Weiss, Paul, 1937-50 (Box Series I-26)
  - Weitzenhoffer, Andre M., 1947 (Box Series I-26)
  - Weller, Marvin, 1946-62 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wells, H. Gideon, 1932-37 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wells, Helen, 1965 (Box Series I-26)
    Bobbs-Merrill Co., Inc.
  - Wentworth, Edward N., 1924-55 (Box Series I-26)
  - Wermuth, Nanny, 1978 (Box Series I-27)
  - Westergaard, M., 1956 (Box Series I-27)
  - Western Reserve University, 1956-58 (Box Series I-27)
    Simon, Webster G.; Honorary Degree; Millis, John S.
  - Westoll, T. Stanley, 1950 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wetherbee, Charles R., 1961 (Box Series I-27)
  - Weyhausen, John, 1951 (Box Series I-27)
  - Weymouth, F.W., 1929 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wha lin, 1924 (Box Series I-27)
  - White, Michael J. D., 1949-56 (Box Series I-27)
  - Whitehouse, H.L.K., 1951 (Box Series I-27)
  - Whiting, Phineas W., 1934-1954; 13.0 Item(s) (Box Series I-27)
    American Association for the Advancement of Science; American Philosophical Society; Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Genetics -- Wasps; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; Oak Ridge National Laboratory; Population genetics; Radiation genetics; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Whitmore, Doris, 1963 (Box Series I-27)
  - Whittaker, Robert, 1950 (Box Series I-27)
  - Whyte, L.L., 1960-61 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wiebe, G.A., 1952 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wiener, Alexander S., 1951 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wiens, John A., 1966 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wiercinski, Floyd J., 1953 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wiggam, A. E., 1920 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wijsman, Robert A., 1951 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wilens, S., 1963 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wiley, John and Sons, Inc., 1956 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wilkerson, Hugh L.C., 1943 (Box Series I-27)
  - Williams, C. B., 1944 (Box Series I-27)
  - Williams, Clarence M., 1933 (Box Series I-27)
  - Williams, George C., 1956 (Box Series I-27)
  - The Williams and Wilkins Co., 1949 (Box Series I-27)
  - Willier, Benj. H., 1934-70 (Box Series I-27)
  - Willson, Mary F., 1966 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wilmont, L. A., 1921 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wilson, Carroll L., [1950] (Box Series I-27)
  - Wilson, Edwin Bidwell, 1938-1954; 11.0 Item(s) (Box Series I-27)
    Berry, L. Joe; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics Record Office; Fisher, Ronald Aylmer; Genetics of plants; Human genetics; Keeler, Clyde A.; Lectures, public speaking; National Academy of Sciences; Pearl, Raymond; Rat genetics; Research support; Sociology; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics
  - Wilson, H. W. Co., 1950 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wilson, J. Waiter, 1944-45 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wilson, James G., 1954 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wilson, Kenneth G., 1974 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wine and Betts, 1921 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wing, DeWitt C., 1923 (Box Series I-27)
  - Winters, L.M., 1932 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wisconsin State Journal, 1972 (Box Series I-27)
  - The Wistar Institute of Anatomy and Biology, 1949-66 (Box Series I-27)
    Farris, E.J.; Kaplan, Martin M.; Koprowski, Hilary; Kozinski, Andrzej W.; Moorehead, Paul S.; Ream, James S; Sturtevant, Mary E.
  - Witschi, Emil, 1943 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wolfe, Roy I., 1949-50 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wolff, George L., 1952-72 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wolfson, Albert, 1951 (Box Series I-27)
  - Woodruff, Lorande Loss, 1945 (Box Series I-27)
  - Woodson, Robert E. Jr., 1961-63 (Box Series I-27)
  - Woodward, Alvalyn E., 1921 (Box Series I-27)
  - Woodyard, Ella, 1936-37 (Box Series I-27)
  - Woolley, George W., 1931-35 (Box Series I-27)
  - Woolston, John E., 1953 (Box Series I-27)
    United Kingdom Scientific Missions
  - Workman, P. L., 1968-69 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wright, G.M., 1948-51 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wright, J.E., 1960 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wright, James E. Jr., 1954 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wright, Johathan W., 1948-53 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wright, Quincy, 1949 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wright, W.H., 1921 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wrobel, Sylvia, 1975-77 (Box Series I-27)
  - Wynn, Dudley, 1957 (Box Series I-27)
  - X-Club, 1952 (Box Series I-27)
  - Yale University, 1949-61 (Box Series I-27)
    Lohmann, Carl; Boell, E. J.
  - Yanai, T., 1972 (Box Series I-27)
  - Yao, Tsoong-Sieu, 1949 (Box Series I-27)
  - Yapp, W.W., 1945-49 (Box Series I-27)
  - Yates, F., 1944 (Box Series I-27)
  - Yoshioka, Evelyn, 1979 (Box Series I-27)
  - Young, C. H., 1951 (Box Series I-27)
  - Young, Duane E., 1953 (Box Series I-27)
  - Young, Gale, 1940 (Box Series I-27)
  - Young, Sanborn, 1916 (Box Series I-27)
  - Young, William C., 1935 (Box Series I-27)
  - Yust, Waiter, 1944-45 (Box Series I-27)
    Encyclopaedia Britannica
  - Zacharias, Leona, 1957 (Box Series I-27)
  - Zimmerman, Elwood C., n.d. (Box Series I-27)
  - Zimring, Daniel L., 1957 (Box Series I-27)
  - Zuckermann, Solly, 1963 (Box Series I-27)
- Series II. Manuscripts, 1.0 Linear feet
  Typewritten, handwritten, and published copies of papers written by Wright, submitted to him for review or comment, or garnered by him in the course of his research. The manuscripts are almost exclusively concerned with Wright's scientific interests, but also include some papers relating to his teaching.
  Manuscripts are arranged by author, title, and year of publication, in that order.
  - Genetics of natural populations. XVIII experiments on chromosomes of Drosophila pseudoobscura from different geographic regions, 1948; 28.0 p.; Dobzhansky, Theodosius Grigorievich, 1900-1975 (Box Series II-1)
    Drosophila genetics; Population genetics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Work of Soviet biologists: theoretical genetics, n.d.; 4.0 p.; Dubinin, Nikolai Petrovich, 1907-1998 (Box Series II-1)
    Genetics; Publication; Russian politics and science
  - Two confused coefficients of relationship: coefficient of relationship and coefficient of genetic similarity II, Frankham. (Box Series II-1)
  - The establishment of chromosomal variance, 1979; Hedrick, Philip W. (Box Series II-1)
  - Regulatory gene adoption: an evolutionary model, 1980; Hedrick, Philip W. and John F. McDonald (Box Series II-1)
  - Genetics of vigor (Abstract), 1951; Hull, Fred H. (Box Series II-1)
  - The organization and purpose of the university, 1944; Hutchins, Robert M. (Box Series II-1)
  - Path analysis: an exposition, 1978; Kang, Kathy M. and E. Seneta (Box Series II-1)
  - Natural selection and blending inheritance, 1930; King, Jack Lester (Box Series II-1)
  - Maintenance of an aminopeptidase allele frequency cline by natural selection, 1980; Koehn, Richard K., Roger Newell, and Frederick Immerman (Box Series II-1)
  - Comments on "Fisher, Wright and path coefficients", 1966; Li, C.C. (Box Series II-1)
  - Maintenance of genetic variability under the joint effect of mutation, selection and random drift, Li, Wen Hsiung (Box Series II-1)
  - [Stochastic theory], 1975; Li, Wen Hsiung (Box Series II-1)
  - Numerical analysis of weak random drift in a cline, Luskin, Mitchell and Thomas Nagylaki (Box Series II-1)
  - Measures of genetic relationship and the concept of fitness, 1978; Michod, Richard E. and Wyatt W. Anderson (Box Series II-1)
  - 1977, Morton, Newton E, and Chin Sik Chung (Box Series II-1)
    - Epidemiologic and genetic issues in retardation, 1977 (Box Series II-1)
    - Preface to Epidemiologic and genetic issues in retardation, 1977 (Box Series II-1)
  - 1974-1978, Nagylaki, Thomas (Box Series II-1)
    - Continuous selective models with mutation and migration, 1974 (Box Series II-1)
    - The correlation between relatives and assortive mating, 1978 (Box Series II-1)
    - The decay of genetic variability in geographically structured populations, 1974 (Box Series II-1)
    - The dynamics of density- and frequency-dependent selection, 1978 (Box Series II-1)
    - The evolution of one and two locus systems, 1975 (Box Series II-1)
    - The island model with stochastic migration, 1978 (Box Series II-1)
    - The moments of stochastic integrals and the distribution of sojourn times, 1974 (Box Series II-1)
    - Quasilinkage equilibrium and the evolution of two-locus systems, 1974 (Box Series II-1)
  - Continuous selective models, 1974; Nagylaki, Thomas and James F. Crow (Box Series II-1)
  - Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences -Physical Sciences, 1980; National Academy of Sciences (Box Series II-1)
  - Newspaper clipping from Jan. 2, 1923, [New York Newspaper] (Box Series II-1)
  - 1979-1981, Orlove, M.J. (Box Series II-1)
    - The elevator effect or a lift in a lift: how a locus in neutral equilibrium can provide a free ride for a neutral a1lele at another locus, 1979-1981 (Box Series II-1)
    - Putting the diluting effect into inclusive fitness, 1979 (Box Series II-1)
    - A reconciliation of inclusive fitness and personal fitness approaches: a proposed correcting term for the inclusive fitness formula, 1979 (Box Series II-1)
  - Coefficients of relationship and coefficients of relatedness in kin selection: a covariance form for the rho formula, 1977-1978; Orlove, M.J. and Constance Wood (Box Series II-1)
  - Scientists revisited: Harvard Studies in Career Development No. 38, 1965; Roe, Anne (Box Series II-1)
  - A chemical model of long-term memory and recall, 1965; Robinson, Charles (Box Series II-1)
  - On following in someone's footsteps: three examples of Lazarsfeld methodology, 1976; Selvin, Hannan C. (Box Series II-2)
  - 1976, Vetta, Atam (Box Series II-2)
    - Parent-child correlation, sib correlation and heritability in Fisher's model of assortive mating, 1976 (Box Series II-2)
    - Quantitative selection and heritability, 1976 (Box Series II-2)
  - Analysis of data on lethals in Drosophila pseudoobscura: the hierarchy of territories, 1947; [Wright, Sewall] (Box Series II-2)
  - The application of path analysis to etiology, 1977; Wright, Sewall (Box Series II-2)
  - Character change, speciation and the higher categories, 1980; Wright, Sewall (Box Series II-2)
  - Comment on "Path Analysis": an exposition by Kang and Seneta, 1978; Wright, Sewall (Box Series II-2)
  - Course Criticism, 1926-1954; [Wright, Sewall] (Box Series II-2)
  - The effects of in-breeding on guinea pigs, 1921; [Wright, Sewall] (Box Series II-2)
  - Final examinations: 300 and 310., 1928-1954; [Wright, Sewall] (Box Series II-2)
  - Heredity and Environment in Relation to Human Intelligence, #1, 1931; [Wright, Sewall] (Box Series II-2)
  - Heredity and Environment in Relation to Human Intelligence, #2, 1931; [Wright, Sewall] (Box Series II-2)
  - Psychophysical identism, panpsychism and science, 1974-1975; Wright, Sewall (Box Series II-2)
  - Random mating with linkage in tetrasomics, 1950-1960; Wright, Sewall (Box Series II-2)
  - The roles of random drift and dispersion in the patterns of distribution of flower color in Linanthus parryae [Epling pencil and galley copy of 1962 manuscript; three copies, unpublished], Wright, Sewall (Box Series II-2)
  - The shifting balance theory in relation to macroevolution. [letter James Crow to Sewall Wright, May 26, 1981], Wright, Sewall (Box Series II-2)
  - Statistical methods in biology, 1931; Wright, Sewall (Box Series II-2)
  - A supposed sheep-goat hybrid and effects of inbreeding on guinea pigs summary [Abstract for Botanical Abstracts, Tandler and Keller], 1919; [Wright, Sewall] (Box Series II-2)
  - Zygotic frequencies, 1956; Wright, Sewall (Box Series II-2)
- Series IIa. Research data and notes, 1928-1973; 1.0 Linear feet (Box Series IIa-1-2)
  Hand-written notes recording experimental results and statistics, compiled by Wright or others, or the analysis of primary data. In some cases, these notes relate to Wright's efforts to verify; presumably, some computations are applications of Wright's "path analysis," and others relate to his work as referee of other people's papers.
  Dobzhansky, Theodosius; Dunn, Leslie Clarence; Epling, Carl; Evolution; Genetics; Genetics -- Mammals; Haldane, John Burdon Sanderson; Population genetics; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc. -- Research data
  - Notes and data, 1928 (Folder Series IIa-1)
    Related to the work of L. C. Dunn
  - Notes and data, 1930 (Folder Series IIa-2)
    Related to the work of J.B.S. Haldane
  - Notes and data, 1930 (Folder Series IIa-3)
  - Notes and data, 1931 (Folder Series IIa-4)
  - Notes and data, 1932-1942 (Folder Series IIa-5)
  - Notes and data, 1933 (Folder Series IIa-6)
    Related to the work of Hogben
  - Notes and data, 1936 (Folder Series IIa-7)
  - Notes and data, 1938 (Folder Series IIa-8)
    Stanford data
  - Notes and data, 1938 (Folder Series IIa-9)
  - Notes and data, 1941-1966 (Folder Series IIa-10)
    Basic data for transect 1941-1966, original ce for 1957 not found 1966 [possibly re: work of Epling]
  - Notes and data, 1942 (Folder Series IIa-11)
    Re: work of Epling
  - Notes and data, 1945 (Folder Series IIa-12)
    Re: work of Dobzhansky
  - Notes and data, 1945 (Folder Series IIa-13)
    [possibly re: work of Dobzhansky] Genetics of natural populations (GNP) XIV, Dobzhansky June 3, 5, 11, 15, 16, 1945
  - Notes and data, 1948 (Folder Series IIa-14)
    Possibly re: GNP XVII originally or GNP XVIII as published, Dobzhansky 1948 Wallace
  - Notes and data, 1950 (Folder Series IIa-15)
  - Notes and data, 1951 (Folder Series IIa-16)
    Bohren 1951
  - Notes and data, 1952 (Folder Series IIa-17)
    Reeves 1953
  - Notes and data, 1954-1955 (Folder Series IIa-18)
  - Notes and data, 1954-1957 (Folder Series IIa-19)
  - Notes and data, 1955 (Folder Series IIa-20)
  - Notes and data, 1955-1960 (Folder Series IIa-21)
  - Notes and data, 1955-1961 (Folder Series IIa-22)
  - Notes and data, 1955-1963 (Folder Series IIa-23)
  - Notes and data, 1956 (Folder Series IIa-24)
    [may be re:
    Draft: Johnson-XI Congress Symbols in Mammalian Genetics
    Cook-Sequential analysis, Macklin
    Cook-copy of letter, Juan 24, 1951
    Paper: Random mating with linkage in tetrasomatics
    Notes: 2/4/56, Zygotic frequencies
  - Notes and data, 1956-1962 (Folder Series IIa-25)
    [Corn?]
  - Notes and data, 1958-1966 (Folder Series IIa-26)
    [Possibly re: work of Epling]
  - Notes and data, 1959 (Folder Series IIa-27)
    Data [projections 3/2/1959]
  - Notes and data, 1959-1962 (Folder Series IIa-28)
  - Notes and data, 1959-1962 (Folder Series IIa-29)
    Clines, Epling, selection, random drift, unique recolonization, random drift-amplified selection, theory of open populations (isolation and distance)
  - Notes and data, 1959-1962 (Folder Series IIa-30)
    [Re: work of Epling]
  - Notes and data, 1960 (Folder Series IIa-31)
    Frequencies as probabilities
  - Notes and data, 1960-1962 (Folder Series IIa-32)
    Analysis-Old [Re: work of Epling]
  - Notes and data, 1962 (Folder Series IIa-33)
    Transect of x2
  - Notes and data, 1962 (Folder Series IIa-34)
    [ Linanthus]
  - Notes and data, 1962 (Folder Series IIa-35)
    Analysis of variables [Re: work of Epling]
  - Notes and data, 1962 (Folder Series IIa-36)
  - Notes and data, 1963-1966 (Folder Series IIa-37)
    Analyses [Re: work of Epling]
  - Notes and data, 1972 (Folder Series IIa-38)
  - Notes and data, 1972 (Folder Series IIa-39)
    [ Linanthus-phenotypes]
  - Notes and data, 1972 (Folder Series IIa-40)
  - Notes and data, 1972-1973 (Folder Series IIa-41)
  - Notes and data, 1972-1973 (Folder Series IIa-42)
  - Notes and data (Folder Series IIa-43)
  - Notes and data (Folder Series IIa-44)
  - Notes and data (Folder Series IIa-45)
    Rr allele
  - Notes and datacombination (Bass) [possibly re: work of Gordon] (Folder Series IIa-46)
    Frequencies of each pattern irrespecive of its original
  - Notes and data (Folder Series IIa-47)
    Analysis of ultraviolet treated series [mutation detection]
  - Notes and data (Folder Series IIa-48)
    Analysis of control series [mutation detection]
  - Notes and data (Folder Series IIa-49)
    [Re: work of C.V. Green]
- Series III. Biographical and autobiographical materials, 1897-1980; 0.5 Linear feet (Box Series III-1)
  Fourteen folders containing resumes and outlines of Wright's life and career. Wright wrote detailed genealogical pieces on his family, with extensive commentary on his own life. Includes a published genealogy of the Wright family, and an illustrated booklet writen by Wright during his childhood.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically
  Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Educational matters; Honors; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Bibliography--Sewall Wright [Dunn], 1912-1937 (Box Series III-1)
  - Biographical data--Sewall Wright, 1965 (Box Series III-1)
  - Birds, 1902 (Box Series III-1)
    Characteristics of birds, notes taken by Sewall Wright
  - Birth and family, 1925 (Box Series III-1)
    Corrections by Sewall Wright
  - Editors Comments on Paper 1-5, April 6, 1976 (Box Series III-1)
  - Memories, Sewall Wright, 1980 (Box Series III-1)
    Green notebook including: family history, theses under Wright's direction, courses, publications, honorary degrees, prizes, societies, offices held, members of the X-Club, Saturday Evening Club, and Wright genealogy
  - North Central Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1936 (Box Series III-1)
    Wright's faculty record